When working with data we may rarely if ever
always need every column from a table. And we
may not need to see every record from a table.
Elsewhere in this course we will cover the SQL
language needed to select information based on
criteria. Here we see a statement for a view,
a view in databases is a saved query,
a view does not store information,
rather it is a storage statement that leads to
getting specific information. For a real-life
analogy it’s like going to the store and looking
in a specific produce section for apples rather
than scanning the entire store for apples. And,
with a view, one does not need to type the same
SELECT statement every time one wants to see a
specific set of records. The statement starts with
a CREATE VIEW and the name of the view, then
we see a SELECT statement that selects from,
but not all the columns from the SALESORDERHEADER
table, and there is a criterion that restricts the
query to just show the orders from just the month
of June 2011. You will also notice that there is
a SELECT statement below this with two dashes
in front of it. These two dashes comment out
the statement, so it will not run at this time.
I am going to execute this CREATE VIEW statement.
And then I will select the
SELECT statement and run it.
And we see the columns and rows from the
SALESORDERHEADER table that are included
in this view. Altering the view is a far
different process than altering a table.
To alter a view the syntax is basically the
same as it is to create a view except we need
to change the keyword CREATE to ALTER. Then I
will add another column to this view, TotalDue,
then I will execute this statement and
the view has been altered. Dropping a
view is similar to dropping a table. I want
to drop this sales view test view, I will type
DROP VIEW Sales.SaleViewTest to drop the
version of this view which I created earlier,
and then I will select and execute the
statement. That view has now been deleted.